<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-30T20:59:52+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Heimdallr</title><subtitle>Multi-Terrain Patrol, Security, and Surveillance Robot</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kinematic Progress</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/23/Kinematics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kinematic Progress" /><published>2020-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/23/Kinematics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/23/Kinematics.html">&lt;p&gt;As before, we have been chugging along with our work. This past week, made a decent bit of headway on the kinematics
of the robot. Nick has been leading the charge on this, and has completed the forward kinematic calculations, and the
inverse kinematics for the legs. Additionally, he is almost done developing the inverse kinematic equations for
how the robot will control the tilt of its body. Once complete, he intends to develop some basic kinematic equations
to help the robot maintain static stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex has been moving ahead with a much more detailed 3D model, that takes into account the strength of the material.
There has also been some discussion about discussing with the AXFAB about the possibilities of use composites on the
robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gabe and trevor have developed a block diagram that details the software components of the robot, and how they 
interact with sensors and actuators. Trevor is now using this to refine the pricing and power consumption data that we
have, and Gabe is using that to help design the ROS framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Gabe is looking into using the Quanser Qbots that are in the robotics lab in order to test some of the software
components.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">As before, we have been chugging along with our work. This past week, made a decent bit of headway on the kinematics of the robot. Nick has been leading the charge on this, and has completed the forward kinematic calculations, and the inverse kinematics for the legs. Additionally, he is almost done developing the inverse kinematic equations for how the robot will control the tilt of its body. Once complete, he intends to develop some basic kinematic equations to help the robot maintain static stability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chugging along</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/16/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chugging along" /><published>2020-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/16/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/16/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;Work on the preliminary design has continued at a steady pace. The basic forward kinematics have been worked out, and
Nick has begun developing the inverse kinematic equations. Trevor has been working on implementing basic walking
simulations in MATLAB. Alex is handling CAD work for both of these projects, while Gabe is learning how ROS works,
to hopefully use it to implement a simulation by the end of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">Work on the preliminary design has continued at a steady pace. The basic forward kinematics have been worked out, and Nick has begun developing the inverse kinematic equations. Trevor has been working on implementing basic walking simulations in MATLAB. Alex is handling CAD work for both of these projects, while Gabe is learning how ROS works, to hopefully use it to implement a simulation by the end of the semester.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginning of the Prelim Work</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/09/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning of the Prelim Work" /><published>2020-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/09/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/09/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;As of Monday the team has finished up the the near continuous presentations on our concept, and begun actual work on the 
project. We have created a preliminary schedule for the work that we will be doing for the rest of the semester, and 
split the tasks up amongst ourselves based on what skills we each have. Currently, work is being done on a preliminary
CAD model, developing kinematic equations for the robot, and selecting the main computer and sensors that the robot will 
use.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">As of Monday the team has finished up the the near continuous presentations on our concept, and begun actual work on the project. We have created a preliminary schedule for the work that we will be doing for the rest of the semester, and split the tasks up amongst ourselves based on what skills we each have. Currently, work is being done on a preliminary CAD model, developing kinematic equations for the robot, and selecting the main computer and sensors that the robot will use.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nearing the end of the planning sprint</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/02/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nearing the end of the planning sprint" /><published>2020-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/02/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/10/02/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;This past week we presented on our team conceptual design to the class, and unveiled our new legged concept. There
was some questions regarding our decision of 4 legs, as it did not entirely line up with our decision matrix, but we
managed to clear most of them up. We have starting working on writing preliminary testing criteria, and will be
presenting them on Monday. Once that is complete, we will have finished up our core planning work, and can get started
on a actually working on the design of the robot, and simulating it in high-fidelity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">This past week we presented on our team conceptual design to the class, and unveiled our new legged concept. There was some questions regarding our decision of 4 legs, as it did not entirely line up with our decision matrix, but we managed to clear most of them up. We have starting working on writing preliminary testing criteria, and will be presenting them on Monday. Once that is complete, we will have finished up our core planning work, and can get started on a actually working on the design of the robot, and simulating it in high-fidelity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Continued Conceptual Design</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/25/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Continued Conceptual Design" /><published>2020-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/25/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/25/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;This past week we finished up the individual conceptual design presentations, and we began work on our group conceptual
design that we will be presenting on Monday. One big change that was made was a decision to move towards a four leg
design, as it will give the robot more multi-terrain capabilities. However, the robot will still have a way to have
motorized wheels attached to it to it, so that it can travel at higher speeds on prepared surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday after our presentations, we are going to take photographs, so hopefully by this time next week the team bio
pages will actually have information on them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">This past week we finished up the individual conceptual design presentations, and we began work on our group conceptual design that we will be presenting on Monday. One big change that was made was a decision to move towards a four leg design, as it will give the robot more multi-terrain capabilities. However, the robot will still have a way to have motorized wheels attached to it to it, so that it can travel at higher speeds on prepared surfaces.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The beginning of conceptual design.</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/18/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The beginning of conceptual design." /><published>2020-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/18/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/18/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;This past week all of the team members developed their own independent proposals for how the robot will accomplish the
requirements that we had previously decided on. We began presenting on these concepts today, with Trevor and Alex
presenting their concepts to the class. On Monday, Nick and I will be presenting our concepts. Once those presentations
have been finished, they will be uploaded to the site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">This past week all of the team members developed their own independent proposals for how the robot will accomplish the requirements that we had previously decided on. We began presenting on these concepts today, with Trevor and Alex presenting their concepts to the class. On Monday, Nick and I will be presenting our concepts. Once those presentations have been finished, they will be uploaded to the site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Weekly Update</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/11/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Weekly Update" /><published>2020-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/11/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/11/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;Background research has been proceeding at a steady pace. Over the past week, we found a number of research papers and
patents that are relevant to our project. A summary of what the sources cover has been uploaded to the documents section.
Additionally, we received feedback from our tech writing professor on our style guide. We have fixed the problems with
and added it to the documents page as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next week we will be developing some rough concepts for the robot’s design. Furthermore, we will soon be
posting an updated version of the requirements document, which will have the spelling and grammar mistakes fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">Background research has been proceeding at a steady pace. Over the past week, we found a number of research papers and patents that are relevant to our project. A summary of what the sources cover has been uploaded to the documents section. Additionally, we received feedback from our tech writing professor on our style guide. We have fixed the problems with and added it to the documents page as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Update</title><link href="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/04/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Update" /><published>2020-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/04/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://heimdallr-robot.github.io/2020/09/04/Update.html">&lt;p&gt;As we just started on the project this past week, not much has happened. The website is pretty much done, and we have a
first pass on the requirements document. See it in the &lt;em&gt;Documents&lt;/em&gt; section on on this website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>roper</name></author><summary type="html">As we just started on the project this past week, not much has happened. The website is pretty much done, and we have a first pass on the requirements document. See it in the Documents section on on this website.</summary></entry></feed>